Are You Watching Closely?
The Prestige is a drama, mystery, science fiction
film directed by Christopher Nolan.
A mysterious story of two magicians whose intense rivalry leads them on a life-long battle for
supremacy -- full of obsession, deceit and jealousy with dangerous and deadly consequences.
Robert Angier, played by Hugh Jackman.
Alfred Borden, played by Christian Bale.
Cutter, played by Michael Caine.
Julia McCullough, played by Piper Perabo.
Sarah, played by Rebecca Hall.
Olivia Wenscombe, played by Scarlett Johansson.
The Prestige is a 2006  science fiction psychological thriller film directed by Christopher Nolan, who co-wrote the
screenplay with his brother Jonathan Nolan and is based on the 1995 novel by Christopher Priest.
It stars Hugh Jackman as Robert Angier and Christian Bale as Alfred Borden, rival stage
magicians in Victorian London who feud over a perfect teleportation illusion.
The cast also features Michael Caine, Scarlett Johansson, Rebecca
Hall, Andy Serkis, and David Bowie as Nikola Tesla.
The film reunites Nolan with actors Bale and Caine from Batman Begins and returning
cinematographer Wally Pfister, production designer Nathan Crowley, and editor Lee Smith.
The Prestige premiered at the El Capitan Theatre on October 17, 2006, was released in the United States on October 20, 2006 and in the United Kingdom on November 10,
2006, by Buena Vista Pictures Distribution through their Touchstone Pictures label in the United States and Canada and internationally by Warner Bros.
Pictures, to positive reviews and grossed $109 million
worldwide against a production budget of $40 million.
It received Academy Award nominations for Best Art
Direction and Best Cinematography.
The film explores themes of dying and death, suicide,
class society, london, england, magic.
The tone is thought_provoking and mind_bending and emotional.